mattfurey.com 2019-11-05

# Privacy Policy

Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. understands that your privacy is important to you. We are committed to protecting the privacy of your personally-identifiable information as you use this website. This Privacy Policy tells you how we protect and use information that we gather from you. By using this website, you consent to the terms described in the most recent version of this Privacy Policy. You should also read our Terms of Use to understand the general rules about your use of this website, and any additional terms that may apply when you access particular services or materials on certain areas of this website. “We,” “our” means Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. “You,” “your,” visitor,” or “user” means the individual accessing this site.

**PERSONAL AND NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Our Privacy Policy identifies how we treat your personal and non-personal information.

**WHAT IS NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION AND HOW IS IT COLLECTED AND USED?**

Non personal information is information that cannot identify you. If you visit this web site to read information, such as information about one of our services, we may collect certain non-personal information about you from your computer’s web browser. Because non-personal information cannot identify you or be tied to you in any way, there are no restrictions on the ways that we can use or share non-personal information.

**WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION AND HOW IS IT COLLECTED?**

Personal information is information that identifies you as an individual, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, and fax number. We may collect personal information from you in a variety of ways:

✓ When you send us an application or other form

✓ When you conduct a transaction with us, our affiliates, or others

✓ When we collect information about in you in support of a transaction, such as credit card information

In some places on this web site you have the opportunity to send us personal information about yourself, to elect to receive particular information, to purchase access to one of our products or services, or to participate in an activity.

**ARE COOKIES OR OTHER TECHNOLOGIES USED TO COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Yes, we may use cookies and related technologies, such as web beacons, to collect information on our website. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you register with us, a cookie helps Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. A web beacon is a small graphic image that allows the party that set the web beacon to monitor and collect certain information about the viewer of the web page, web-based document or e-mail message, such as the type of browser requesting the web beacon, the IP address of the computer that the web beacon is sent to and the time the web beacon was viewed. Web beacons can be very small and invisible to the user, but, in general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page or e-mail, including HTML based content, can act as a web beacon. We may use web beacons to count visitors to the web pages on the web site or to monitor how our users navigate the web site, and we may include web beacons in e-mail messages in order to count how many messages sent were actually opened, acted upon or forwarded.

Third party vendors also may use cookies on our web site. For instance, we may contract with third parties who will use cookies on our web site to track and analyze anonymous usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and members. Such information is shared externally only on an anonymous, aggregated basis. These third parties use persistent cookies to help us to improve the visitor experience, to manage our site content, and to track visitor behavior. We may also contract with a third party to send email to our registered [users/members].

To help measure and improve the effectiveness of our e-mail communications, the third party sets cookies. All data collected by this third party on behalf of Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. is used solely by or on behalf of Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. and is shared externally only on an anonymous, aggregated basis. From time to time we may allow third parties to post advertisements on our web site, and those third-party advertisements may include a cookie or web beacon served by the third party. This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of information collected from you by third party ad servers. We do not control cookies in such third party ads, and you should check the privacy policies of those advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology before linking to an ad.

We will not share your personal information with these companies, but these companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you, and they may share your personal information that you provide to them with others.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. websites you visit.

**HOW DOES Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. USE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. may keep and use personal information we collect from or about you to provide you with access to this web site or other products or services, to respond to your requests, to bill you for products/services you purchased, and to provide ongoing service and support, to contact you with information that might be of interest to you, including information about products and services of ours and of others, or ask for your opinion about our products or the products of others, for record keeping and analytical purposes and to research, develop and improve programs, products, services and content.

Personal information collected online may be combined with information you provide to us through other sources We may also remove your personal identifiers (your name, email address, social security number, etc). In this case, you would no longer be identified as a single unique individual. Once we have de-identified information, it is non-personal information and we may treat it like other non-personal information. Finally, we may use your personal information to protect our rights or property, or to protect someone’s health, safety or welfare, and to comply with a law or regulation, court order or other legal process.

**DOES Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH OTHERS?**

We will not share your personal information collected from this web site with an unrelated third party without your permission, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy. In the ordinary course of business, we may share some personal information with companies that we hire to perform services or functions on our behalf. In all cases in which we share your personal information with a third party for the purpose of providing a service to us, we will not authorize them to keep, disclose or use your information with others except for the purpose of providing the services we asked them to provide.

We will not sell, exchange or publish your personal information, except in conjunction with a corporate sale, merger, dissolution, or acquisition. For some sorts of transactions, in addition to our direct collection of information, our third party service vendors (such as credit card companies, clearinghouses and banks) who may provide such services as credit, insurance, and escrow services may collect personal information directly from you to assist you with your transaction. We do not control how these third parties use such information, but we do ask them to disclose how they use your personal information before they collect it. If you submit a review of the Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc., during the submission process we ask your permission to gather your basic information (such as name and email address) which we then share with the third party for whom you are submitting the review. We may be legally compelled to release your personal information in response to a court order, subpoena, search warrant, law or regulation.

We may cooperate with law enforcement authorities in investigating and prosecuting web site visitors who violate our rules or engage in behavior, which is harmful to other visitors (or illegal). We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we feel that the disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or property, protect someone’s health, safety or welfare, or to comply with a law or regulation, court order or other legal process. As discussed in the section on cookies and other technologies, from time to time we may allow a third party to serve advertisements on this web site.

If you share information with the advertiser, including by clicking on their ads, this Privacy Policy does not control the advertisers use of your personal information, and you should check the privacy policies of those advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology before linking to an ad.

**HOW IS PERSONAL INFORMATION USED FOR COMMUNICATIONS?**

We may contact you periodically by e-mail, mail or telephone to provide information regarding programs, products, services and content that may be of interest to you. In addition, some of the features on this web site allow you to communicate with us using an online form. If your communication requests a response from us, we may send you a response via e-mail. The e-mail response or confirmation may include your personal information. We cannot guarantee that our e-mails to you will be secure from unauthorized interception.

**HOW IS PERSONAL INFORMATION SECURED?**

We have implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personally-identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction. Only authorized personnel and third party vendors have access to your personal information, and these employees and vendors are required to treat this information as confidential. Despite these precautions, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized persons will not obtain access to your personal information.

**LINKS**

This site contains links to other sites that provide information that we consider to be interesting. Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.

**PUBLIC DISCUSSIONS**

This site may provide public discussions on various business valuation topics. Please note that any information you post in these discussions will become public, so please do not post sensitive information in the public discussions. Whenever you publicly disclose information online, that information could be collected and used by others. We are not responsible for any action or policies of any third parties who collect information that users disclose in any such forums on the web site. Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. does not agree or disagree with anything posted on the discussion board. Also remember that you must comply with our other published policies regarding postings on our public forums.

**HOW CAN A USER ACCESS, CHANGE, AND/OR DELETE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

You may access, correct, update, and/or delete any personally-identifiable information that you submit to the web site. You may also unsubscribe from mailing at any time by selecting the “unsubscribe” option at the bottom of any email from Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc..

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. will not intentionally collect any personal information (such as a child’s name or email address) from children under the age of 13. If you think that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, please contact us.

**CHANGES**

Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. reserves the right to modify this statement at any time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be listed in this section, and if such changes are material, a notice will be included on the homepage of the web site for a period of time. If you have any questions about privacy at any websites operated by Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. or about our website practices, please contact us at: matt@mattfurey.com

**Data Protection Policy**

Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. is committed to providing a superior learning experience for everyone we work with. We know that our users are committed to their success and we are equally committed to ensuring that each interaction that someone has with our content is optimized for maximum educational potential. To enable us to do this, Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. needs to gather and use certain information about individuals.

Individuals who we gather information about includes customers, affiliates, business contacts, employees, and other people the organization has a relationship with or may need to contact. This policy describes how this personal data is collected, handled, and stored to meet the company’s data protection standards — and to comply with the law.

**Why This Policy Exists**

This data protection policy ensures Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc.:

✓ Complies with data protection law and follows industry best practices  
✓ Protects the rights of staff, customers, affiliates, and partners  
✓ Is open about how it stores and processes individuals’ data  
✓ Protects itself from the risks of a data breach

**EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Protection Law**

The GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) protection law describes how organizations who conduct business with individuals or entities located in EU (European Union) nations — including Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. — must collect, handle, and store personal information. These rules apply regardless of whether data is stored electronically, on paper, or in any other manner. To comply with the law, personal information must be collected and used fairly, stored safely, and not disclosed unlawfully.

**The EU GDPR is underpinned by eight core principles. These state that personal data must:**

✓ Be processed fairly and lawfully  
✓ Be obtained only for specific, lawful purposes  
✓ Be adequate, relevant, and not excessive  
✓ Be accurate and kept up to date  
✓ Not be held for any longer than necessary  
✓ Processed in accordance with the rights of data subjects  
✓ Be protected in appropriate ways

Not be transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA), unless that country or territory also ensures an adequate level of protection.

**1\. Policy Statement**

Every day our business will receive, use, and store personal information about our customers, affiliates, partners, and colleagues. It is important that this information is handled lawfully and appropriately, in line with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation (collectively referred to as the ‘Data Protection Requirements’). We take our data protection duties seriously, because we respect the trust that is being placed in us to use personal information appropriately and responsibly.

**2\. About This Policy**

This policy and any other documents referred to in it, sets out the basis on which we will process any personal data that we collect or process. This policy does not form part of any employee’s contract of employment and may be amended at any time. The company as a whole is responsible for ensuring compliance with the Data Protection Requirements and with this policy. Any questions about the operation of this policy or any concerns that the policy has not been followed should be referred in the first instance to the Data Protection Officer.

**3\. What is Personal Data?**

Personal data is defined as data, (whether stored electronically or paper based) relating to a living individual who can be identified directly or indirectly from that data, (or from that data and other information in our possession). Processing is any activity that involves use of personal data. It includes obtaining, recording, or holding the data, organizing, amending, retrieving, using, disclosing, erasing, or destroying it. Processing also includes transferring personal data to third parties under privacy control conditions. Sensitive personal data includes contact info, address, session activity on the platform, IP location etc. Sensitive personal data can only be processed under strict conditions, and used for express purpose that it was collected for.

**4\. Data Protection Principles**

Anyone processing personal data, must ensure that data is: Processed fairly, lawfully and in a transparent manner. Collected for specified, explicit, and legitimate purposes and any further processing is completed for a compatible purpose. Adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary for the intended purposes. Accurate and where necessary, kept up to date. Kept in a form which permits identification for no longer than necessary for the intended purposes. Processed in line with the individual’s rights and in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction, or damage, using appropriate technical or organizational measures. Not transferred to people or organizations situated in countries without adequate protection and without firstly having advised the individual.

**5\. Fair and Lawful Processing**

The Data Protection Requirements are not intended to prevent the processing of personal data, but to ensure that it is done fairly and without adversely affecting the rights of the individual. In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we will only process personal data where it is required for a lawful purpose. The lawful purposes include (amongst others): whether the individual has given their consent, the processing is necessary for performing a contract with the individual, for compliance with a legal obligation, or for the legitimate interest of the business. When sensitive personal data is being processed, additional conditions must be met.

**Collection of Information**

We receive and store information about you such as:

Information you provide us: We collect information you provide to us which includes: your name, email address, address or postal code, payment method, and telephone number. We collect this information in a number of ways, including manual entry while you are using our service, interact with our customer service, participate in surveys or marketing promotions, provide reviews or ratings, taste preferences, set preferences in Your Profile/Account, or otherwise provide information to us through our service or elsewhere.

**Information we collect automatically:  **

We collect information regarding you and your use of our service, your interactions with us and our advertising, as well as information regarding your computer or other device used to access our service.

This information includes:

✓ Your activity on our platform such as course progress and search queries  
✓ Details regarding your interactions with customer service such as the date, time and reason for contacting us  
✓ Transcripts of any chat conversations that you initiate on our platforms  
✓ In the event that you initiate phone support, your phone number  
✓ Device IDs or unique identifiers, device and software characteristics (such as type and configuration)  
✓ Connection information, statistics on page views, referral URLs, IP address, and standard web log information  
✓ Information collected via the use of cookies, web beacons and other technologies, including ad data (such as information on impressions delivered to a cookie, the site URL where the impression was delivered, as well as the date and time).  
We use the information we collect to provide, analyze, administer, enhance, and personalize our services and marketing efforts, to process your registration, your orders, your payments, and your communication on these and other topics.

Our primary aim is always to enhance the user experience. We do so in several ways using the data that we collect, but a few examples are: determining your general platform usage, required action item completions, login details, etc. which then helps us know what difficulties the you’re facing within the platform, with which can then use to take action to minimize the effort on your end. We collect other information, such as most visited links on our website, which then help us conclude what content was most watched, enabling us to create additional content geared toward our users’ needs and personal preferences.

**6\. Processing for Limited Purposes**

In the course of our business, we may collect and process personal data, which may include data that we receive directly from a data subject and data we receive from other sources including location data, business partners, and subcontractors who work technical, payment and delivery services, credit reference agencies, and other capacities.

We will only process personal data for the specific purposes or for any other purposes specifically permitted by the Data Protection Requirements. We will notify those purposes to the data subject when we first collect the data or as soon as possible thereafter.

**7\. Notifying Individuals**

If we collect personal data directly from an individual, we will inform them about:

The purpose or purposes for which we intend to process that personal data, as well as the legal basis for the processing.  
Where we rely upon the legitimate interests of the business to process personal data, the legitimate interests pursued.  
The types of third parties, if any, with which we will share or disclose that personal data.

The fact that the business intends to transfer personal data to a non-EEA country or international organization and the appropriate and suitable safeguards in place.

How individuals can limit our use and disclosure of their personal data.

Information about the period that their information will be stored or the criteria used to determine that period.  
Their right to request from us as the controller access to and rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing.

Their right to object to processing and their right to data portability.

Their right to withdraw their consent at any time (if consent was given) without affecting the lawfulness of the processing before the consent was withdrawn.

The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

Other sources where personal data regarding the individual originated from and whether it came from publicly accessible sources.

Whether the provision of the personal data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract, as well as whether the individual is obliged to provide the personal data and any consequences of failure to provide the data.

The existence of automated decision-making, including profiling and meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the individual.

If we receive personal data about an individual from other sources, we will provide them with this information as soon as possible (in addition to telling them about the categories of personal data concerned) but at the latest within One (1) month. We will also inform data subjects whose personal data we process, that we are the data controller with regard to that data and our contact detail regarding data protection act is matt@mattfurey.com

**8\. Adequate, Relevant and Non-Excessive Processing**

We will only collect personal data to the extent that it is required for the specific purpose notified to the data subject.

**9\. Accurate Data**

We will ensure that personal data we hold is accurate and kept up to date. We will check the accuracy of any personal data at the point of collection and at regular intervals afterwards. We will take all reasonable steps to destroy or amend inaccurate or out-of-date data.

**10\. Timely Processing**

We will not keep personal data longer than necessary for the purpose or purposes for which it was collected. We will take all reasonable steps to destroy or erase from our systems, all data which is no longer required.

**11\. Processing in line with Data Subject’s Rights**

We will process all personal data in line with data subjects’ rights, in particular their right to:

Confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning the individual is being processed.

✓ Request access to any data held about them by a data controller.

✓ Request rectification, erasure or restriction on processing of their personal data.

✓ Lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

✓ Data portability.

✓ Object to processing including for direct marketing.

✓ Not be subject to automated decision making including profiling in certain circumstances.

**12\. Data Security**

We will take appropriate security measures against unlawful or unauthorized processing of personal data and against the accidental or unlawful destruction, damage, loss, alteration, or unauthorized disclosure of or access to personal data transmitted, stored, or otherwise processed.

We will put in place procedures and technologies to maintain the security of all personal data from the point of the determination of the means for processing and point of data collection to the point of destruction. Personal data will only be transferred to a data processor if he or she agrees to comply with those procedures and policies, or if he or she puts in place adequate measures himself/herself.

We will maintain data security by protecting the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the personal data, defined as follows:

Confidentiality: Only people who are authorized to use the data can access it.

Integrity: Personal data should be accurate and suitable for the purpose for which it is processed.

Availability: Authorized users should be able to access the data if they need it for authorized purposes. Personal data should therefore be stored on the Matt Furey, Matt Furey Enterprises, Inc. and/or Gold Medal Publications, Inc. central computer system & databases instead of individual PCs.

Our Security Procedures:

Entry controls: Any stranger seen in entry-controlled areas will be reported.

Securing lockable desks and cupboards all the time. Desks and cupboards should be kept locked if they hold confidential information of any kind. (Personal information is always considered confidential.)

Data minimization will be practiced.

Pseudonymisation and encryption of data will be the primary state of storing the data.

Methods of disposal: Paper documents would be shredded. Digital storage devices would be physically destroyed when they are no longer required. Electronic data would be deleted once it’s intended purpose is fulfilled.

Equipment: Staff has to ensure that individual monitors do not show confidential information to passers-by and that they log off from their PC when it is left unattended.

Transferring Personal Data Outside of the EEA: We may transfer any personal data we hold to a country outside the European Economic Area (‘EEA’) or to an international organization, provided that one of the following conditions applies:

The country to which the personal data is transferred ensures an adequate level of protection for the data subjects’ rights and freedoms.

The data subject has given his consent.

The transfer is necessary for one of the reasons set out in the Act, including the performance of a contract between us and the data subject, or to protect the vital interests of the data subject.

The transfer is legally required on important public interest grounds or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

The transfer is authorized by the relevant data protection authority where we have adduced adequate safeguards with respect to the protection of the data subjects’ privacy, their fundamental rights and freedoms, and the exercise of their rights.

Subject to the requirements above, personal data we hold may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Those staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of contracts with the data subject, the processing of payment details and the provision of support services.

**13\. Disclosure and Sharing of Personal Data**

We may share personal data we hold with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in: https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2006/46/section/1159

**14\. Subject Access Requests**

To these ends, the company has a privacy statement setting out how data relating to individuals is used by the company.  
Individuals must make a formal request for information we hold about them. Employees who receive a request should forward it to the data department immediately.

When receiving telephone inquiries, we will only disclose personal data we hold on our systems if the following conditions are met:

We will check the caller’s identity to make sure that information is only given to a person who is entitled to it.

We will suggest that the caller put their request in writing if we are not sure about the caller’s identity and where their identity cannot be checked.

Where a request is made electronically, data will be provided electronically when possible.

Our support team will refer a request to the data processing department or the Data Protection Compliance Manager for assistance in difficult situations.

**15\. Changes to this Policy**

We may modify this Privacy Statement at any time, but we will provide prominent advance notice of any material changes to this Statement, such as posting a notice through the Services, on our websites, or sending you an email, to provide you the opportunity to review the changes and choose whether to continue using the Services. For detailed information on GDPR, please visit https://www.eugdpr.org/
